Ing. Jakub Sochor, Ph.D.



Contact Information

jakub@sochor.me https://sochor.me

Butzenstrasse 44 Zurich, 8038 Switzerland

Profile

I am a Software Engineer and a Researcher with a focus on Computer Vision (CV) and Machine Learning (ML).

I have experience from various environments. I have worked as a researcher and have multiple top-level first-author publications. Furthermore, I have worked at a company on applied CV & ML research. Finally, I have led and owned projects with multiple team members contributing to the projects at Google. The features, I have launched at a global scale while working on Google Assistant, are used by hundreds of thousands of Assistant users daily. An extended online version of the resume can be found at sochor.me.

Professional Experience

Google

Software Engineer – level 4 (08/2019 - present, Zurich)

- As a member of Proactive Google Assistant, I owned and led various projects utilising Machine Learning methods at Google
- Multiple team members have worked on the projects I have led and the features I have launched are used by hundreds of thousands of users

PTC

Senior Deep Learning Engineer (08/2018 - 07/2019, Zurich)

- I was a key team member working on a project that used ML methods for 6 DoF object pose estimation with only 3D models for training
- The feature was commercially launched as a part of Vuforia Engine

Vlatacom

Computer Vision Developer (11/2017 – 01/2018, Belgrade)

• The outcome of the secondment was a proof of concept for the application of fine-grained vehicle classification and vehicle colour recognition in the context of Vlatacom's requirements

Brno University of Technology

Researcher – Computer Vision & Machine Learning (11/2013 - 07/2018, Brno)

• I made contributions to the design of DNNs published in top journals and conferences (CVPR, CVIU, etc.) – sochor.me/publications

Further details and the complete history is at sochor.me/experience

Skills

Machine Learning Computer Vision Project Leadership

Programming Languages

Python, C++

Libraries and Tools

Tensorflow, NumPy, Abseil Docker, Git, Bazel MapReduce Microservices

Languages

English – fluent Czech – native German – basic

Education – Brno University of Technology

Ph.D. (06/2014 - 06/2018)

- Focus on Computer Vision and Machine Learning methods
- First-author publications in top journals and conferences (CVPR, CVIU, etc.) see <u>sochor.me/publications</u> for the list of all the publications
- Thesis topic: Automatic Traffic Video Surveillance: Fine-Grained Recognition of Vehicles and Automatic Speed Measurement

Master's degree (09/2012 - 06/2014)

- Field of study: Mathematical Methods in Information Technology
- Thesis topic: Traffic Analysis from Video
- Graduated with honours

Bachelor's degree (09/2009 – 06/2012)

- Field of study: Information Technology
- Thesis topic: Fast Detection of Traffic Signs in Image
- Graduated with honours